Guide to the Hallie Flanagan Papers, circa 1890-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VIII. AUDIO RECORDINGS and TRANSCRIPTS, 1967-1985
  - Interviews by Joanne Bentley
    - Students (Vassar) - Jane Whitebread Levin, VC 1936 and Muriel Fox White, VC 1935, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.425)
    - Students (Vassar) - Mary McCarthy, VC 1933, 1982; (TRS) (Folder 55.426)
    - Students (Vassar) - Harriet Meyer, VC 1931, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.427)
    - Students (Vassar) - Eleanor Phelps, VC 1928, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.428)
    - Students (Vassar) - Claudia Hatch Stearns, VC 1929, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.429)
    - Students (Vassar) - Mary St. John Villard, VC 1934, 1979; (TRS) (Folder 55.430)
    - Students (Vassar) - Dorothy Wallace, VC 1933, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.431)
    - Students (Smith) - Doris Abramson, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.432)
    - Students (Smith) - Robert Baron, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.433)
    - Students (Smith) - Ted Kazanoff, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 55.434)
    - Colleagues and friends - Daniel Aaron, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.435)
    - Colleagues and friends - Philip Barber, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.436)
    - Colleagues and friends - Howard Bay and Howard Bolton, 1980, 1984; (TRS) (Folder 56.437)
    - Colleagues and friends - George Dowell, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.438)
    - Colleagues and friends - Rosamond Gilder and Josephine Gleason, 1982; (TRS) (Folder 56.439)
    - Colleagues and friends - Suzanne Johnston, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.440)
    - Colleagues and friends - George Kondolf, 1984; (TRS) (Folder 56.441)
    - Colleagues and friends - Gordon Post, [198?]; (TRS) (Folder 56.442)
    - Colleagues and friends - Phelps and Ted Riley, 1980, 1982; (TRS) (Folder 56.443)
    - Colleagues and friends - Irwin Rubenstein, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.444)
    - Colleagues and friends - Bob Schnitzer, 1979; (TRS) (Folder 56.445)
    - Colleagues and friends - Henry and Mark Schubart, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.446)
    - Colleagues and friends - Denton Snyder, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.447)
    - Colleagues and friends - Kay Strelsky, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.448)
    - Colleagues and friends - Lauralee and Day Tuttle, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.449)
    - Colleagues and friends - Ruth and Vernon Venable, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.450)
    - Colleagues and friends - Patsy and Bill Walsh, 1980; (TRS) (Folder 56.451)
    - Colleagues and friends - Halsted Welles, 1985; (TRS) (Folder 56.452)
  - Interviews by George Mason University
    - Relatives - Eric Bentley, 1976; (2 tapes) (Folder 55.413)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - William Farnsworth, 1977; (TRS) (Folder 56.453)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Bud Fishel, undated; (TRS) (Folder 56.454)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Rosamond Gilder, undated; (TRS) (Folder 56.455)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Gordon Graham, undated; (TRS) (Folder 56.456)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Paul Green, 1975; (TRS) (Folder 56.457)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - John Houseman, 1976; (TRS) (Folder 56.458)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - George Izenour, [1977?]; (TRS) (Folder 56.459)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - George Kondolf, 1976; (TRS) (Folder 57.460)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Esther Porter Lane, 1976; (TRS) (Folder 57.461)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Emmet Lavery, 1977; (TRS) (Folder 57.462)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Kate Lawson, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.463)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Ned Lehac, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.464)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Norman Lloyd, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.465)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Dorothea Lynch, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.466)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - J. Howard Miller, 1976; (TRS) (Folder 57.467)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Irwin Rubinstein, 1977; (TRS) (Folder 57.468)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Arnold Sundgaard, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.469)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Converse Tyler, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.470)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Halsted Welles, 1975; (TRS) (Folder 57.471)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Duncan Whiteside, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.472)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Miscellaneous excerpts, undated; (TRS) (Folder 57.473)
    - Colleagues and friends (Federal Theatre Project) - Florence Kerr, 1967; (TRS) (Folder 57.474)
- SERIES IX. FAMILY HISTORY and BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, circa 1916-1980
  - HFD: General, non-printed material
    - List of materials at the University of North Carolina, undated (Folder 58.475)
    - List of materials in the Smith College Archives, undated (Folder 58.476)
    - General biographical materials, undated; (for clippings see box 28) (Folder 58.477)
    - Contract with Coward-McCann for Shifting Scenes, 1928 (Folder 58.478)
    - Contract with Duell, Sloane and Pearce, Inc. for Arena, 1939 (Folder 58.479)
    - Will and financial material, 1947-1957 (Folder 58.480)
    - Letters to children regarding disposal of her possessions, 1947 Jan 4; (photocopy) (Folder 58.481)
    - Biographical piece written for "Dr. Wheelis,", 1948 Aug; (TS, annotated by Shirley Rich Krohn) (Folder 59.505)
  - HFD: Unpublished biographical essays/articles
    - Speech given upon HFD's departure from Vassar, given by Grace M. Macurdy, 1942; (TS carbon) (Folder 58.482)
    - Madam Director, by Dorothy Colman Wallace, 1938; (TS) (Folder 58.483)
    - Hallie Flanagan, by Myra Page, 1940s-1950s; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.484)
    - Memorial Service, 1969 Sep 16; (TS) (Folder 58.485)
    - Hallie Flanagan--the Smith Years, by Janet Clarke, 1975; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.486)
    - Paper by Linda Scaporrotti, 1975; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.487)
    - Article by Kay Hocking, VC 1929 [written for Vassar Quarterly but never published], 1979; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.488)
    - Hallie Flanagan, by Alice Tomlinson, [197?]; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.489)
    - Hallie Flanagan Davis--the Smith Years-- Portrait of the Artist as Educator, by Helen Chinoy, 1970s-1980s; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.490)
    - Hallie Flanagan, by Helen Krich Chinoy, 1970s-1980s; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.491)
    - Hallie Flanagan--Her Role in American Theatre, 1924-1936, by Barbara Mendoza, 1970s-1980s; (photocopy of TS; excerpts) (Folder 58.492)
    - A Quest for Perfection, by Howard Wicks, circa 1980; (photocopy of TS) (Folder 58.493)
    - Unidentified excerpts, undated; (photocopy) (Folder 58.494)
    - Materials received by Joanne Bentley from the Federal Bureau of Investigation after filing a FOIA request, undated (Folder 57.474a)
  - Family History
    - Ferguson Family: New Hampshire; Madison County, IL, undated (Folder 59.495)
    - Ferguson Family: Macoupin County, IL (Brighton); St. Louis, MO, undated (Folder 59.496)
    - Ferguson Family: Omaha, NB; Redfield, SD, undated (Folder 59.497)
    - Ferguson Family: Poweshiek County, IA (Sonora); Grinnell, IA, undated (Folder 59.498)
    - Ferguson Family: La Grange, IL; Leffler Electric System, undated (Folder 59.499)
    - Fischer Family, undated (Folder 59.500)
    - John Murray Flanagan, undated (Folder 59.501)
    - Philip Haldane Davis, undated (Folder 59.502)
    - Philip Haldane Davis - Material from notebook, circa 1916-1940 (Folder 59.503)
    - Frederic F. Flanagan, undated (Folder 59.504)
    - Joanne Davis Bentley, undated (Folder 59.505)
- Series X. 2025 ADDITION, 1925-1976
  - Clippings - Articles about Hallie Flanagan and the Vassar Experimental Theater, 1928-1973 (Folder 92.506)
  - Clippings - Articles by Hallie Flanagan, 1927-1939 (Folder 92.507)
  - Federal Summer Theatre - Correspondence and planning, 1937 (Folder 92.508)
  - Federal Summer Theatre - "First Federal Summer Theatre…A Report", [1937?] (Folder 92.509)
  - Federal Theatre Bulletin, Vol. 2, No. 2 and 5, 1937 (Folder 92.510)
  - Federal Theatre Project - "A Review of the Productivity and Service of the Play Bureau", 1936 (Folder 92.511)
  - Federal Theatre Project - "Federal Theatre Productions by American Playwrights", undated (Folder 92.512)
  - Federal Theatre Project - Play lists and synopses, 1936-1938 (Folder 92.513)
  - Federal Theatre Project - "What Was Federal Theatre?" by Hallie Flanagan, undated (Folder 92.514)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence, 1932-1934 (Folder 92.515)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence, 1935-1938, undated (Folder 92.516)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence re: appointment of director of the Federal Theatre Program, 1935 Jul (Folder 92.517)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence re: Guggenheim Fellowship, 1925-1932 (Folder 92.518)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence to/from MacCracken, Henry Noble, 1932-1941 (Folder 92.519)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence to/from Theatre Arts Monthly, 1926-1933 (Folder 92.520)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Correspondence to/from Theatre Guild Magazine, 1931-1935 (Folder 92.521)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - "Meeting of the Advisory Council of the Anglo-American Institute of the First Moscow University, 1934 Nov (Folder 92.522)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Vassar College, course planning, 1925-1939 (Folder 92.523)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Vassar College, course planning, exams, 1930-1935 (Folder 92.524)
  - Flanagan, Hallie - Vassar College, proposal for a major in Drama, 1937 (Folder 92.525)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Folder 92.526)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - Correspondence, Grinnell College, 1973-1974 (Folder 92.527)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - "Dynamo" by Hallie Flanagan, annotated, circa 1975; [photocopy] (Folder 92.528)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - Federal Theatre project ephemera, 1975 (Folder 92.529)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - "Hallie Flanagan: Her Role in American Theatre, 1924-1935," abstract, circa 1973 (Folder 92.530)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - "Hallie Flanagan: and the Vassar Experimental Theatre" by Ellen Brent Senay Jones, annotated, circa 1973; [photocopy] (Folder 92.531)
  - Mendoza, Barbara - Notes, circa 1973 (Folder 92.532)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Letters from Hallie Flanagan to the V.E.T., 1934 Feb-May (Folder 92.533)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Negatives, undated (Folder 92.534)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Photographs, undated (Folders 92.535-92.536)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Reference photographs and notes, undated (Folder 92.537)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Plays list, 1925-1935 (Folder 92.538)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Productions, "Antony and Cleopatra", 1934-1974 (Folder 92.539)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Program, "The Marriage Proposal", 1928 Mar 3 (Folder 92.540)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Script, "Blocks" by Molly Day Thacher, 1933 (Folder 92.541)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - Script, "The Dream of Vasav Adatta," translated by A. G. Shirreff and Panna Lall, 1933 (Folder 92.542)
  - Vassar Experimental Theatre - "Summer Session in the Theatre", 1935 Jun-Aug (Folder 92.543)